RG 069:046, Aaron Gaylord Papers
Connecticut State Library
Aaron Gaylord papers
1792-1819
Connecticut State Library
Gaylord, Aaron
6 cubic feet
Aaron Gaylord of Hartford, Conn. was a merchant and ship owner. The papers consist of correspondence, accounts and miscellaneous business papers relating to his local accounts and shipments on various vessels.
RG069_046
1912-012
Scope and Content
Correspondence, accounts and miscellaneous business papers of Aaron Gaylord relating to his local accounts and shipments on various vessels.
Related Material
Aeolus (ship), log of the voyage 1806-1807 and accounts of Aaron Gaylord, supercargo 1806-1809. Call number: 387 Ae71.
Index Terms
Subjects:
American Hero (Brig); Ann (Sloop); Catharine (Schooner); Catharine (Sloop); Concord (Brig); Daphne (Brig); Grey Hounds (Brig); Henry & Gustavus (Schooner); Hiram (Brig); Hiram (Schooner); Juno (Sloop); London (Ship); Merchants -- Connecticut; Mountainer (Brig); Neptune (Brig); Polly (Schooner); Ralph (Sloop); Sally (Schooner); Shipping -- Accounting; Ships -- Connecticut; Victory (Sloop)
Places:
Connecticut; Hartford (Conn.)
Persons:
Gaylord, Aaron
Document Types:
Account books; Clippings; Contracts; Correspondence; Financial records; Legal documents; Licenses; Reports
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
This collection was a gift of Mrs. Emma Joyner McKenney of Farmington on December 26, 1911. Parts of the collection have been called the Sarah Gaylord Wells Collection and the Emma Joyner McKenney Collection.
Container List
- Series 1. Ships Papers, 1793-1809
  - Brig American Hero account papers, 1801 (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
  - Brig American Hero correspondence, 1801 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Brig Concord account papers, 1807-1808 (Box 1, Folder 10-12)
  - Brig Concord correspondence, 1808-1809 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Brig Daphne account papers, 1797 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Brig Grey Hounds account papers, 1809 (Box 1, Folder 15-19)
  - Brig Hiram account papers, 1798-1799 (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
  - Brig Mountainer account papers, 1806-1807 (Box 2, Folder 7-11)
  - Brig Neptune account papers, 1799 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Schooner Catharine account papers, 1800-1801 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Schooner Catharine - third voyage - account papers, 1801 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
  - Schooner Catharine - fourth voyage - account papers, 1801-1802 (Box 3, Folder 6-9)
  - Schooner Henry and Gustavus account papers, 1799-1800 (Box 3, Folder 10-12)
  - Schooner Hiram account papers, 1809 (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
  - Schooner Polly account papers, 1793 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Schooner Sally account papers, 1803-1805 (Box 4, Folder 2-5)
  - Schooner Sally correspondence, 1803 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Ship London account papers, 1801-1802 (Box 4, Folder 7-9)
  - Sloop Ann account papers, 1800-1802 (Box 4, Folder 10-17)
  - Sloop Ann correspondence, 1800-1801 (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
  - Sloop Ann - first voyage - account papers, 1799-1800 (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
  - Sloop Ann - first voyage - account papers, 1800 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sloop Ann - second voyage - account papers, 1800-1801 (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
  - Sloop Ann - third voyage - account papers, 1800 (Box 5, Folder 4-10)
  - Sloop Ann - fourth voyage - account papers, 1800-1801 (Box 5, Folder 11-13)
  - Sloop Ann - fifth voyage - account papers, 1799-1801 (Box 5, Folder 14-19)
  - Sloop Ann - fifth voyage - account papers, 1801-1802 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Sloop Ann - fifth voyage - correspondence, 1800-1801 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Sloop Catharine account papers, 1800-1801 (Box 6, Folder 4-10)
  - Sloop Catharine correspondence, 1800-1801 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Sloop Catharine - first voyage - account papers, 1800-1801 (Box 6, Folder 12-13)
  - Sloop Catharine - second voyage - account papers, 1801 (Box 6, Folder 14-16)
  - Sloop Catharine - second voyage - correspondence, 1801 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Sloop Catharine - fifth voyage - account papers, 1802 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Sloop Catharine - fifth voyage - correspondence, 1802 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Sloop Juno account papers, 1794 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Sloop Ralph account papers, 1799-1803 (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
  - Sloop Victory account papers, 1793-1794 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Series 2. Business Papers, 1792-1819
  - Account book, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Amsterdam current price list, 1793 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Bank of the State of Georgia - bank notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Bills and receipts, 1792-1802, 1806, 1809 (Box 7, Folder 11-13)
  - Bills of sale, 1794-1801 (Box 7, Folder 14-16)
  - Blank affidavits, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1801-1802 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - debt, 1797-1803 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Envelopes and miscellaneous slips, 1797-1799 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Gaylord, Moses estate papers, 1794-1808 (Box 8, Folder 4-5)
  - Holkins/Reynolds correspondence, 1795-1796 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Holkins/Reynolds legal papers, 1792-1798 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Inspection reports, 1792-1794 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Liquor licenses, 1794-1795 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Seymour, Captain F. estate papers, 1801-1803 (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
  - Ship building contracts, 1792-1795 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Smith, Ruben papers, 1792-1798 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Wage slips, 1800 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Accounts, 1792-1793; 1 volume (Volume Item 1)
  - Accounts, 1794-1803; 1 volume (Volume Item 2)
  - Accounts, 1794-1796; 1 volume (Volume Item 3)
  - Ledger A, 1794-1802; 1 volume (Volume Item 4)
  - Index to ledger A, 1 volume (Volume Item 5)
  - Waste book, 1794-1796; 1 volume (Volume Item 6)
  - Waste book, 1796-1798; 1 volume (Volume Item 7)
  - Accounts, 1792-1819; 1 volume (Volume Item 8)
    May contain information regarding payroll and shipping.
  - Ship book number 1, 1798-1802; 1 volume (Volume Item 9)
    Contains accounts for outfitting and cargo.